Guide to the Barack Obama presidential campaign and inauguration collection, 2008-2012.
Obama, Barack, presidential campaign and inauguration collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Barack Obama presidential campaign and inauguration collection, 2008-2012.
6828
RMC Staff
7.2 cubic feet.
Memorabilia, newspapers, printed ephemera, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Obama t-shirt and bumper sticker, and an extensive collection of newspapers and magazines about his Presidential campaign and inauguration.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Obama t-shirt and bumper sticker, and an extensive collection of newspapers and magazines about his Presidential campaign and inauguration. Magazines include many photographs of Michelle Obama and the Obama family as well as images of President Obama.
Obama t-shirts, hat, signs, bumper stickers, and buttons, collected from the campaign in Richmond, Virginia.
Items from the Obama inauguration including posters, newspapers, magazines, flyers, pins, invitations, and other ephemera. Includes an Obama Christmas ornament, and a key ring with ribbons from Miller and Rhoades, a now-defunct Richmond, VA department store.
Also newspapers, clippings, and other memorabilia, largely from the Chicago Tribune, the New York Times, and other Chicago sources from the first year of Obama's presidency.
Campaign items from the 2012 election.
Obama t-shirts, hat, buttons, bumper stickers, iPhone case and "Victory Counsel Virginia Voter Advocate Training Manual," collected by Larry Palmer, 2012.
Three lawn signs (New Mexico for Obama, Native Americans for Obama, Hispanics for Obama) and a New Mexico Obama button.
Cornell Daily Sun, November 7, 2012 and Inauguration “invitation,” 2012.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Obama, Barack.; Obama, Michelle, 1964-; Obama family.
Subjects:
Presidents--United States--Elections--2008.; Campaign paraphernalia.; Elections--United States.; Political campaigns--United States.; Inauguration Day.; Presidents--United States--Inauguration.
Form and Genre Terms:
Ephemera.; T-shirts.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Books by and about President Obama are cataloged separately.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Newspapers
  - Buffalo News: November 5 [final edition], 2008 (Box 1)
  - Ithaca Journal: November 5, 2008 (Box 1)
  - New York Times: November 5 [late edition (2 copies)], 2008 (Box 1)
  - New York Times: packaged late edition, November 5 (not same as previous item); and January 21, 2009, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Journal do Brasil: November 6, 2008 (Box 5)
  - O Globo: November 6, 2008 (Box 5)
  - New York Times: A13-14, A-23-24, January 15, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Ithaca Journal: 5B-8B, January 16, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Ithaca Journal: USA Weekend, January 16-18, 2009 (Box 5)
  - New York Times: Weekend Arts, C29-C-38, January 16, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Wall Street Journal: W1, January 16, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Ithaca Journal: January 20, 2009 (Box 5)
  - USA Today: January 20, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Ithaca Journal: Inauguration 2009 Special Section, January 21 (2 copies) (Box 5)
  - New York Times: A, C, D, P sections, January 21, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch: January 21, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Wall Street Journal: January 21, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Washington Post: January 21, 2009 (Box 5)
  - The Epoch Times: January 22-28, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Ithaca Journal: USA Weekend, January 30-February 1, 2009 (Box 5)
  - New York Times: February 25, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Assorted news clippings, January 2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Assorted news clippings, February 2008 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Assorted news clippings, June 2008 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Assorted news clippings, August 2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Assorted news clippings, September 2008 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Assorted news clippings, October 2008 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Assorted news clippings, November 2008 (Box 8, Folder 9-12)
  - Assorted news clippings, December 2008 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Assorted news clippings, January 2009 (Box 8, Folder 14-16)
  - Assorted news clippings, February 2009 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Assorted news clippings, March 2009 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Assorted news clippings, April 2009 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Assorted news clippings, May 2009 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Assorted news clippings, June 2009 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Assorted news clippings, July 2009 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Assorted news clippings, August 2009 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Assorted news clippings, September 2009 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Assorted news clippings, October 2009 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Assorted news clippings, November 2009 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Assorted news clippings, December 2009 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Assorted news clippings, January 2010 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Assorted news clippings, February 2010 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Assorted news clippings, March 2010 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Assorted news clippings, April 2010 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Assorted news clippings, May 2010 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Assorted news clippings, Undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Cornell Daily Sun and Inauguration “invitation”, November 7, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Assorted news clippings, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2006, 2007, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2013 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Assorted news clippings, 2014 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Series II: Magazines
  - America's Hope/Barack Obama, January 20, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic, Special State of the Union Issue, January-February, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Black Enterprise, March, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Columbia, Winter, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Denver Magazine, August, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - E/the Environmental Magazine, March/April, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Economist/The World in 2009 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Esquire, 1/20/09 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Essence: the Obamas/Portrait of America's New First Family, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Globe, 2/2/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jewel, the Presidential Edition, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Life & Style Weekly, 2/2/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mad, 2/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Metro Weekly, 1/15/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Michelle Obama, Commemorative Edition, 04/2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Michelle Obama, Collector's Edition, Historical, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mother Jones, 02/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York magazine, "All new" issue, 1/19-26/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York Times Magazine, 1/18/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New Yorker, 2/11&18, 3/17, 7/21, 9/8, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - New Yorker, 10/2, 13, 27, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - New Yorker, 11/17, 12/8/08; 1/19, 26/09, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Newsweek, 1/19/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - O/The Oprah Magazine, 4/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Obama/The Dream Fulfilled, 1/20/09 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Obama/the 44th President/Hope, 11/08, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Obama/44th President of the United States, Historical Collectors' Edition, 3/08, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - OK Weekly!, 2/2/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - People, 2/2/09, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The Source, 11/08, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Time, 1/20, 26/09, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Today's Black Woman, 3/09, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - TV Guide, 1/26-2/8/09, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - U. S. News & World Report/Secrets of the Civil War, Collectors' Edition, 10/08, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Utne Reader, 1-2/2009 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vogue, 3/09, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - African American Pride, Collector's Edition, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Street Wise, December 3-9, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Chicago Collection, winter 2008 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Journey to the Presidency, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The New York Times Magazine, January 18, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Chicago Street Wise, January 21-27 and January 28-February 3, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The New Yorker (cover), January 26, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Chicago, February, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Today's Chicago Woman, March, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Chicago Tribune Magazine, March 22, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Time, August 10, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - New York, August 10-17, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Rolling Stone, August 20, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The New York Times Magazine, November 1, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The New York Times Magazine, October 17, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - National Review, Special Post-Shellacking Issue, November 29, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Series III: Memorabilia
  - Obama for President (hat), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Yes We Did/Obama Biden (tee shirt), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Obama '08/BarackObama.com (tee shirt), 2008 (Box 2)
  - "This union may never be perfect, but generation after generation has shown that it can always be perfected." Philadelphia, PA 3.18.8 (tee shirt), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Historical Democratic National Convention/Denver 08 August 25-28/Obama for President (tee shirt), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Obama/Biden/WWW.DEMOCRATICSTUFF.COM (tee shirt), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Vote 11.4.08 (tee shirt), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Polling place information (door knob signs [3]), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Obama '08 (sign), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Veterans for Obama (sign), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Obama/Biden (sign), 2008 (Box 2)
  - For the change we need vote November 4th (12-1/2" round sign, stickers), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Buffalo News, November 5 (printer's plates), 2008 (Box 3)
  - 2009 Inauguration (wall calendar) (Box 3)
  - Arrest Bush / Obama Inauguration (sign), 2008 (Box 3)
  - Christmas tree ornament (hand-crafted), 2008 (Box 4)
  - Key holder (hand decorated), 2008 (Box 4)
  - Obama/Biden (buttons [2]), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Obama '08 (button), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Obama '08 for President (button), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Obama (button), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Barack Obama/2008 (button) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Barack Obama Welcomes You to the Democratic National Convention/Denver, Colorado/August 25-28, 2008 (button) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Women for Obama (button), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1908-"100th Anniversary"-2008/Democratic National Convention, Denver, CO - August 25-28, 2008 (button) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - America's First Family: Barack, Michelle, Malia, Sasha, Obama '08 for President (button), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Obama (bracelet), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - I Voted 2008 Presidential Election (2 stickers) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Obama/Biden (6 round stickers [various sizes]), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hope (magnet), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Obama/Biden 2008 (magnet) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Independents for Obama (bumpersticker), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Our Moment is Now (campaign letter), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Thank you letters (2), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - VCU employees donate mostly to Obama (news article), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sandwich identification stickers (2 sheets), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Obama Biden Plan to support working women and families (booklet), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Change Can't Wait! Turn Virginia Blue in '08 (convention program), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mark Warner U S Senate (bumpersticker), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Obama State Delegate Info (document), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia / 2008 State Convention Schedule (document) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Delegate pre-filing form (document), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Caucus Declaration Form (document), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Rules Committee (document), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Richmond City Democratic Committee: Bylaws and proposed change, 4/2008 (document) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Richmond City Democratic Committee: Agenda and minutes, 4/24/08 (document)), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Obama comics (news report), 2009 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - www.barackbust.com (advertisement), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Obamarama (advertisement), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Inauguration (bookmark), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Inauguration (invitation), 2009 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Commemorative (photograph), 2009 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University Africana Center Inauguration celebration information (document), 2009 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The People's Inaugural LGBT Gayla (flyer), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stop the U.S. War of Terror & Torture (flyer), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Walking Detour Routes for 56th Presidential Inaugural (map), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Obama wall calendar (packet), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 44 Presidents (postcard), 2009 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - President Barack Obama (postcard), 2009 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 2012 Campaign Letter and 2011 Commemorative Presidential Print (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Inauguration Program and Poster, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cards (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Campaign mailings, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Interesting Inaugural facts (flyer), 2008 (Box 7)
  - Posters, banners, and an Inauguration t-shirt (Box 9)
  - Presidential pleated bunting, MU-1370 (Box 10)
  - 2012 campaign ephemera including t-shirts, hats, bumper stickers, signs, buttons, iPhone case, voter manual, and two old-fashioned glasses with the Obama for America logo etched into the side of the glass, 2012; MU-2021 (Box 11)
  - Welcome to O Virginia Headquarters (sign), 200- (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Obama/Biden (sign), 2008 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Mailings and stickers, 2012-2013 (Box 12, Folder 1)